Guide to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Photographs, 1914-present CTC.1966.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Productions, 1938-2011; I.; 1021.0 photographs
  - Steel Magnolias, 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Ellen Renestene, Marie Teets, Chris Zuenie, Marzie Dagenhard, Betty Tolbert, and Renee Stettner.
  - Steel Magnolias - Promethea Theatre, 1999; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph shows Amy Toothman as Annelle and Brenda Walker as M'Lynn in Steel Magnolias. The play was Promethea Theatre production at the Pit Theatre in 1999.
  - Stop the World - I Want to Get Off, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    Stop the World - I Want to Get Off was presented by Robert Morris College Colonial Theater from September 4-13, 1980. Photograph is of Chris Clark and Helen Anson.
  - Stop the World - I Want to Get Off - Oliver Plaza Dinner Theatre, 2.0 photographs
    This folder contains two photographs of Oliver Plaza Dinner Theatre's production of Stop the World - I Want to Get Off including Lisby Larson and Franz Lion.
  - Strange Snow, 1985; 3.0 photographs
    Strange Snow was presented by the Pittsburgh Public Theater from January 8 - February 10, 1985. Photographs are of Marshall W. Mason (director), Judd Hirsch, Trish Hawkins, Kevin McCLarnon, Matthew Cowles, and Lanford Wilson (author).
  - Street Car Named Desire, 1966; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Barton Heyman, Winifred Mann, Carolee Campbell, and John Simpson. This Pittsburgh Playhouse production was performed in 1966.
  - Streetcar Named Desire, 1973; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Anna Strasberg and Norman Ornellas. This Pittsburgh Playhouse production was performed in 1973.
  - The Stuff We're Saving Up, April 1978; 1.0 photograph
    The folder contains one photograph of Pennsylvania Repertory Theatre's production of The Stuff We're Saving Up at the Lion Walk Arts Center including Camilla Schade and Joseph Uher.
  - The Subject was Roses, 1976; 2.0 photographs
    The Subject was Roses was presented by the Red Barn Theatre from June 18 - July 4, 1976. Photographs are of Mary Alice Bialock and Bingo O'Malley.
  - The Suicide, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    The Suicide was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from November 20 - December 12, 1980 at the Kresge Theatre. This photograph is of Jeff Laite.
  - Suicide in B Flat, 1979/1980; 2.0 photographs
    This folder contains two photographs of Soho Repertory Theatre's production of Suicide in B Flat including Laurie Kapner as Laureen, Lisa Polansky, and Lamont Arnold as Petrone.
  - A Sunbeam, 1991; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Paul Bates and Mary Alice. This Pittsburgh Public Theater production was performed from May 30 - July 7, 1991.
  - The Sunshine Boys, 1995; 2.0 photographs
  - The Sunshine Boys, Oct. 1976; 1.0 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the Monroeville Civic Theatre's production of The Sunshine Boys.
  - Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street - Carnegie Mellon University, 1985; 1.0 photograph
    Sweeney Todd was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from June 21 - August 10, 1985 at Hartwood Acres. This photograph is of Jeremy Mann, Risa Brainin, and Julia Collins.
  - Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street - Pittsburgh Pubic Theater, 1996; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Brooks Almy, Ted Pappas, and Steve Barton. This Pittsburgh Public Theater production was performed from January 11 - February 18, 1996.
  - Sweet Charity, Sept. 19, 1976; 2.0 photographs
    This folder contains two photographs of Stage 62's production of Sweet Charity.
  - Sweet Talk, 1981; 2.0 photographs
    Sweet Talk was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from November 12-21, 1981 at the Kresge Theatre. These photographs are of Kelvin R. Shepard, Carl Lumbly, and Cathleen Lea Harvey.
  - Sweethearts, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    Sweethearts was presented by the Pittsburgh Metropolitan Stage Company from May 21 - June 8, 1980. Photograph is of Michael Cook and Jim Boerlin.
  - Sylvia, 1998; 1.0 photograph
    Sylvia was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 1-13, 1998. Photograph is of Caitlin Larsen, Sharon Connelly-Schaller, and Doug Rees.
  - Sylvia Plath: A Dramatic Portrait, 1982; 3.0 photographs
    Sylvia Plath: A Dramatic Portrait was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from March 26 - April 25, 1982. Photographs are of Janet Robb, Caryl Opshinsky, and Patricia Grace.
  - Table Manners, July 1991; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Christopher Peters and Linda Holeva. This Robert Morris production was performed in July 1991 at the Robert Morris Colonial Theater.
  - Taken in Marriage - White Barn, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    Taken in Marriage was presented by the White Barn Theatre from June 3-14, 1980. Photograph is of cast members Susan Boyle, Rosemary Meyerjack, Mary Lyn Certo, Virginia McMillan, and Cathi Mari Mannella.
  - Taken in Marriage - Fine Line Theatre Co., 1981; 2.0 photographs
    These photographs shows cast members of Taken in Marriage. Included in the photos are Elise Paquette, Lisa Bradley, Jerry Walsh, Bonnie Gillmore, and Florence Palumbo. The Fine Line Theatre Company play was performed in the St. Peter's Annex building October 30th through November 22nd, 1981.
  - Tales from the Vienna Woods, 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Jeff Detweiler and Rachel Wynn. This University of Pittsburgh Theatre production was performed at the Studio Theatre located in the basement of the Cathedral of Learning.
  - Talley's Folly, 1999; 1.0 photograph
    Talley's Folly was presented by Mountain Playhouse from May 30 - June 14, 1999. Photograph is of Doug Rees and Holly Thuma.
  - The Taming of the Shrew, 1994; 2.0 photographs
    Photographs are from the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival production of the Taming of the Shrew. It was performed at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre June 30th through July 16th, 1994. Appearing in the photos are James Andreassi as Petruchio, Kate Levy as Katherina, and Chappale Burton and Scott Ferrara as servants. The photographer was Kimberly Pasko.
  - A Taste of Honey, 1982; 1.0 photograph
    A Taste of Honey was presented by Duquesne University from November 17-20, 1982. Photograph is of Lydia Sadouskas and Alan Morris.
  - Teibele and Her Demon, 1.0 photograph
    This photograph shows actors Debra Gordon as Teibele, David Case as Menasha, and Amy Hartman as Genendel in Teibele and Her Demon. The Jewish Theatre of Pittsburgh production played at the Jewish Community Center Theater in Squirrel Hill during February of an unknown year.
  - Ten Times Table, July 8th, 1984; 1.0 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the Winter Company's production of Ten Times Table including Dick Wise and John Donnelly.
  - Terra Nova, 1981; 1.0 photograph
    Terra Nova was presented by the Pittsburgh Public Theater from January 1 - February 15, 1981. Photograph is of Jack Ryland and John C. Vehhema.
  - There Goes the Bride, 2001; 2.0 photographs
    There Goes the Bride was presented by Mountain Playhouse from August 21 through September 2nd, 2001. This photograph is of cast members Neil A. Casy and Emily Elsener.
  - Thomas A. Edison, 1979; 3.0 photographs
    Thomas A. Edison was presented by the Iron Clad Agreement from September 21-22, 1979. Photographs are of M.M. Melozzi, James R. Krut, K. Wilson Hutton, and Mark Harlow.
  - Thou Shalt Not, 2008; 6.0 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    This file contains a CD-R disc with 6 images from Point Park University's Conservatory Theatre Company production of Thou Shalt Not. The play was performed January 31st through February 10th, 2008. The images show various members of the cast.
  - A Thousand Clowns, 1984; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph is of actors Beth Andrachick Hauptle and Carroll Hauptle. The Orchard Performing Arts production was staged at the Apple Hill Playhouse July 25th through August 4th, 1984.
  - 3 by 2, A Romantic Revue, 1979; 2.0 photographs
    These two photographs show cast members of 3 by 2, A Romantic Revue. Included in the photos are Robert Koch, Bonnie Gilmore, Fred Donatelli, Carinna Carpentieri, and John Waterson. One of the photos is from Pop People, a skit that opened the show. The Fine Line Theatre Company play was performed at the Lion Walk Performing Arts Center in Oakland February 9th-24th, 1979.
  - Toad of Toad Hall, 1976; 1.0 photograph
    Toad of Toad Hall was presented by the Pittsburgh City Players from March 21 - April 25, 1976.
  - Tom Jones, 1982; 1.0 photograph
    Tom Jones was presented by Pittsburgh Public Theater from September 9 - October 24, 1982. Photograph is of Anne Kerry and Don Howard.
  - Top Girls, 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Hillary Hoft. This was a University of Pittsburgh production.
  - Travesties, 1981; 2.0 photographs
    These photographs show cast members Tim Rogers, Ruth Ann Rooney, and Ellen Haggerty. This Allegheny Repertory Theatre production was performed at the Fine Line Cultural Center November 27th through December 19th, 1981.
  - Troilus & Cressida, 1974; 1.0 photograph
    Troilus & Cressida was presented by Duquesne University from November 13-23, 1974. Photograph is of unidentified cast members.
  - True Beauties, 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Collen Madden, Jeri Misler, Shawn Ebbert, and Ilona Haris. This University of Pittsburgh Theatre production was performed from October 9 - 24 at the Studio Theatre in the basement of the Cathedral of Learning in Oakland.
  - True West, January 1983; 1.0 photograph
    Included in this file is one photograph of Ken Bolden and Sam Lane, cast members of the Fine Line Theatre Company's production of Sam Shepard's True West. The play was staged at the Famous Rider Cultural Center in Oakland, January 7-30, 1983.
  - Tuesday, 1976; 1.0 photograph
    Tuesday was presented by the Pittsburgh City Players from July 8 - August 8, 1976. Photograph is of Ian Schneiderman, Warren Bowles, Nat Ritch, and Steve Pearson.
  - Twelfth Night - Carnegie-Mellon University, 1981; 1.0 photograph
    Twelfth Night was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from February 12-21, 1981 at the Kresge Theatre. This photograph is of Phillip Safley and Mary Jane Lewis.
  - Twelfth Night - Duquesne University, 1984; 1.0 photograph
    Twelfth Night was presented by Duquesne University from March 14-17, 1984. Photograph is of Art DeConcilis, Susan Abi-Nader, Mark A. Calla, Teresa Zajicek, Marcella Sotereanos, and Cheryl Oris.
  - Twelfth Night - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, 1992; 4.0 photographs
    Photographs are from the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival's Young Company's production of Twelfth Night. It was performed at the Pit Theatre July 24th through August 15th, 1992. Appearing in the photos are David Hardinger as Malvolio, Kevin McDonald as Sir Andrew Aguecheek, D.E. Jukes as Sir Toby Belch, Robert J. Masterson as Fabian, Michelle DiMaso as Viola, Ron Richards as Duke Orsino, and Candice Brown-McDonald as Olivia. The photographer was Kimberly Pasko.
  - Two for the Seesaw, 1979; 3.0 photographs
    Two for the Seesaw was presented by the Red Barn Theatre from June 15 - July 1, 1979. Photographs are of Joe Di Stio and Elaine Carlson.
  - Two Into One, May 1996; 1.0 photograph
    This file contains one photograph from Comtra Theatre's production of Two Into One. Appearing in the photo are the majority of the cast. The play was performed in May, 1996.
  - Two Gentlemen of Verona, 2004; 2.0 photographs
    The folder contains two images of the 2004 Playhouse Conservatory Company's production of Two Gentlemen of Verona. The first image features Allison Reed as Julia, Mark August Spitznagel as Proteus, and Sean Greney as Thurio. The second images features Christopher Proud as Launce, Jeremy Rierson as Crab, and Christopher Gatterdam as Speed. Photos courtesy of Lighthouse Photography.
  - Under Milk Wood, 1981; 2.0 photographs
    Under Milk Wood was presented by the Pittsburgh Metropolitan Stage Company from February 14 - March 8, 1981. Photographs are of Shirley Tannenbaum, Tom Spinella, Steven Levy, Michael Cook, Susan Chapek, and Jim Boerlin.
  - The Unlit Corridor, 1978; 1.0 photograph
    The Unlit Corridor was presented by the Theatre Express during the 1977/1978 season. Photograph is of Susan Cash.
  - U.S.A., 1988; 1.0 photograph
    U.S.A. was presented by Robert Morris College Colonial Theater from April 8-17, 1988. Photograph is of cast members Randall Lucas, Rich Ivaun, Ralph Valenzi, Regina Novak, Cindy Fisher, and Karen Kownacki.
  - Vanities, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    Vanities was presented by the White Barn Theatre from April 11 - May 3, 1980. Photograph is of Dinah Mason, Cheri Mason, and Karen Rafferty.
  - A Very Rich Woman, 1.0 photograph
    This file contains one photograph from Comtra Theatre's production of A Very Rich Woman. Appearing in the photo are actors Bob Bankert as Linus Bailey, Leonard Schmidt, as the Supervisor, Dick Westrick as Oliver Sears, and Renee Martin-Stettner. The play was performed in June of an unknown year.
  - Victorian Mystery Adventure, 1.0 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the Pittsburgh Center for the Arts production of Victorian Mystery Adventure.
  - Volpone or the Fox, 1977; 1.0 photograph
    Volpone or the Fox was presented by the Pittsburgh City Players from March 25 - April 23, 1977. Photograph is of Barbara Knowles.
  - Wait Until Dark, 1976; 2.0 photographs
    Wait Until Dark was presented by the Red Barn Theatre from August 8-24, 1975. Photographs are of Victor Cornelius, Sarah Chodoff, Joe DeStio, Brooks MacKay, and Katie Karlovitz.
  - Waiting for Godot - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1984; 1.0 photograph
    Waiting for Godot was presented by Pittsburgh Public Theater from April 6 - May 20, 1984. Photograph is of Avner Eisenberg, David Hurst, Larry John Meyers, and Stephen von Benschoten.
  - Waiting for Godot - University of Pittsburgh, 2001; 3.0 photographs
    Waiting for Godot was performed at the Henry Heymann Theatre by the University of Pittsburgh Repertory Theatre September 19th through October 7th, 2001. Appearing in the photographs are actors Doug Mertz as Pozzo, Matt Gaydos as Lucky, Larry John Meyers as Vladimir, and Alex Coleman as Estragon.
  - Watching Fire, Watching Rain, 16.0 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    This file contains 16 thumbnail images of scenes from Samuel Hazo's Watching Fire, Watching Rain. The images include David Crawford as Ben Santos, Nancy Bach as Rosalind Revere, Karen Baum as Benedicta Santos, and Jet Canary as Jimmy Czrnywyz. This world premiere Jewish Theatre of Pittsburgh production played at the Katz Center for the Performing Arts at the Jewish Community Center of Greater Pittsburgh, August 31st through September 17th, 2006. The images are on one sheet of paper and are also stored on a CD-R disc.
  - War, 1991; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of David Tompkins, Joyce Sterling, and Christopher Stierheim. This Laurel Highlands Regional Theatre production was performed in 1991.
  - Welcome to LaLa, 1978; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph shows cast members of Welcome to LaLa. Included in the photos are Robert Koch, Bonnie Gilmore, Fred Donatelli, Richard Caughey, and John Waterson. The Fine Line Theatre Company play was performed at the Lion Walk Performing Arts Center in Oakland July 13th through August 12th, 1979.
  - What the Butler Saw - Chatham College, 1975; 1.0 photograph
    What the Butler Saw was presented by Chatham College from June 13-29, 1975 at the Chatham College Theatre. This photograph is of cast members Patricia Lipton, Nancy E. Hirsch, and Dick Rauh.
  - What the Butler Saw - Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre, 1982; 3.0 photographs
    What the Butler Saw was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from July 9 - August 7, 1982. Photographs are of Laurel Fardella, Ray Cupples Jr., Kate Royston, and Mark J. Dolasnky.
  - Who Killed Victor Malloy?, 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of the cast of Who Killed Victor Malloy?. This was a Flying Pig Theatre production.
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, 1983; 4.0 photographs
    Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? was presented by Pittsburgh Public Theater from March 24 - May 8, 1983. Photographs are of April Shawhan, Timothy Donoghue, Alan Mixon, and Melissa Hurst.
  - The Who's Tommy, 1997; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Amana Crocker and Shari Richards. This Gargaro Production was performed from April 30 - May 6, 1997 at the Byham Theatre.
  - Wild Oats, 1998; 2.0 photographs
    Wild Oats was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 16-27, 1998. These photographs are of David Garwood, Amy Barker, Doug Rees, and Mark Baker.
  - The Woman in Black, 1999; 1.0 photograph
    The Woman in Black was presented by Mountain Playhouse from June 22 - July 4, 1999. Photograph is of Charles Tuthill and Douglas Rees.
  - The Women, 1986; 1.0 photograph
    The Women was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from February 12-22, 1986. This photograph is of the cast members.
  - The Woolgatherer, 1990; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Martha Ranii and John Gresh. This Upstairs Theatre production was performed from June 21 - July 7, 1990.
  - Working, 1.0 photograph
    This file contains one photograph from Comtra Theatre's production of Working. Appearing in the photo are a majority of the cast of the production. The play was performed in July and August of an unknown year.
  - Woyzeck, 1977; 4.0 photographs
    Woyzeck was presented by Theatre Express from April 18 - May 3, 1977 at the Chatham College Theatre. Photographs are of Randell Haynes,Taunya Pettiford, and Susan Cash.
  - You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown - Oliver Plaza Dinner Theatre, March 1976; 2.0 photographs
    This folder contains two photographs of Oliver Plaza Dinner Theatre's production of You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown,. The second photograph includes Richard Locke.
  - You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown - Mountain Playhouse, 2001; 2.0 photographs
    You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown was presented by Mountain Playhouse from August 7-19, 2001. Photographs are of Neil A. Casey, Tom Schaller, Brian Duguay, and Janet Dickinson.
  - Zara Spook and Other Lures, 2002; 1.0 photograph
    Open Stage Theatre's production of Zara Spook and Other Lures was performed May 24th through June 8th, 2002 at the Henry Heymann Theatre. Appearing in the photo are cast members Naomi Grodin, Sara Gaille, Christopher Kirsch, and Shelby Wyzykowski.
  - Zito & Bean, 1982; 1.0 photograph
    Zito & Bean performed at the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre on June 24, 1982. Photograph is of Chris Zito and Steve Bean.
- Theatres, 1914-1980; II.; 91.0 photographs
  This series contains images of Theatre buildings. Many of the photos are from the City Photographer's Collection. For the most part they are exterior shots. The series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Academy Theatre, 1.0 print
    Located on Liberty Avenue near Wood Street. Photocopy of photograph from the Carnegie Library's Pennsylvania Room.
  - Aldine Theatre, May 5, 1935; 1.0 photograph
    The Aldine Theatre was located at the corner of Liberty Avenue and Oak Alley. It was also known as the Victoria, the Senator, and from 1950-1976 the New Nixon Theatre. This photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Alvin Theatre, 1937; 13.0 photographs
    The Alvin Theatre was located at 115 Sixth Street. It opened in 1891 and was also known as the Shubert-Alvin, the New Harris-Alvin, the Senator J.P. Harris, and finally the Gateway Theater. Ten of the photographs are negatives reproduced from the Merriman Scrapbook collection. Please note that those originals are from 1908, but these negatives were created in the 1990s.
  - Auburn Theatre, July 7, 1932; 1.0 photograph
    The Auburn Theatre was located on Baum Boulevard. This photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Enright Theatre, 1933-1935; 2.0 photographs
    The Enright Theatre was located in East Liberty on Penn Avenue. The Enright opened in 1928. These photographs show street views from the Enright. One photograph shows the Enright marquee. This photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Fulton Theatre, November 14, 1937; 3.0 photographs
    Originally built in 1903 as the Gayety Theater, the Pittsburgh Cultural Trust purchased this 1300-seat venue, then called the Fulton Theater, in 1988. The Trust renovated and reopened the Fulton in 1991. The theater was renamed the Byham Theater in 1995, in recognition of a gift from William C. and Carolyn M. Byham. These photographs are of the Fulton Theater from Sixth Street. These photographs are from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Gayety Theatre, April 19, 1915; 2.0 photographs
    The Gayety Theatre was originally built in 1903. Other names of this theatre include the Fulton and the Byham. These photographs are images of the Gayety Theatre on Penn Avenue from Duquesne Way. This photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Grand Opera House, 3.0 photographs
    This file contains photographic negatives of advertisements and programs related to the Grand Opera House. Unfortunately, we do not have any photos of the Grand Opera House structure. Included in the file are images of a Chimes of Normandy broadside from March 4, 1878, the front cover of a Grand Opera House program from August 27, 1906, and a February 1, 1925 Pittsburgh Post advertisement for the Dark Swan.
  - Grand Theatre, September 23, 1932; 1.0 photograph
    The Grand Theatre was a motion picture theatre located at 1851 Centre Avenue. Part of the Irene Kaufman Settlement House can be seen in the photo. This image is from the City Photographer's Collection.
  - Kenyon Theater, September 7, 1939; 2.0 photographs
    Photographs are from Federal and Erie Streets. The Kenyon Theatre was built in 1909 and remained in ownership by the Kenyon family until 1919. The theatre remained standing until it was demolished for the raising of Allegheny Center. This photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Liberty Theatre, 1914; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is a street view of the Liberty Theatre on Liberty Avenue. This photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Liberty Theatre - Southside, 16.0 photographs
    The Liberty Theatre was located at 1200 East Carson Street in the Southside. Photographs show the Michaels brothers (owners) and family, the exterior of the theatre, and unidentified shows performed there. Collection also includes original negatives of the photographs.
  - Loew's Theatre, 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is from 6th Street and Fort Duquesne Boulevard looking South. Photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Lyceum Theatre, May 2, 1915; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is from Penn Avenue from Barkers Way. Photograph is part of the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Miles Theatre, May 2, 1915; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of the Miles Theatre on Penn Avenue. Photograph is taken on the north side of the street looking west at Sandusky Street. Photograph is part of the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - New Leona Theatre, 1.0 photograph
    The New Leona Theatre was opened in 1927 as the Stahl Million Dollar Theatre. The New Leona Theatre was located in the Homestead section of Pittsburgh.
  - Nickelodeon, 1.0 photograph
    The original Nickelodeon was built in June 1905 by John Paul Harris. The Pittsburgh Nickelodeon was located on Smithfield Street. Please note that this is a photograph of an artist's rendering of the entrance to the theatre.
  - Nixon Theatre, 1950; 4.0 photographs